<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lipdverse</title>
    <link>https://lipdverse.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on lipdverse</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lipdverse.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loading LiPD data in Python</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/blog/2022/10/28/2022-10-28-loading-lipd-data-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/blog/2022/10/28/2022-10-28-loading-lipd-data-in-python/</guid>
      <description> Python is a powerful tool for paleoclimate science, and we often get asked how to load large libraries of LiPD files into python for subsequent analysis. The “lipd” package, available on pip, handles LiPD input and output in python, however, it can be difficult to use. We’re working on creating a new, powerful and modern package (pylipd), but in the meantime, here’s a practical tutorial by Michael Erb.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome the LiPDverse</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/blog/2022/10/21/2022-10-20-welcome-the-lipdverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/blog/2022/10/21/2022-10-20-welcome-the-lipdverse/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the LiPDverse! The LiPDverse has been around for awhile now, but we’ve redesigned the website, added a blog, and did a bit more, so if even if you’re a regular, this looks a bit new. So now that you’re here, what should you do?
1. Explore LiPD datasets We created the LiPDverse exists to be a simple and convenient way of accessing and exploring LiPD-formatted datasets. The primary way of doing this is by exploring the compilation projects hosted here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wNAm</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/project/wnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/project/wnam/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The wNAm database is a collection of Holocene temperature, hydroclimate, and circulation records from western North America. This is a dynamic compilation, meaning that new datasets that meet the criteria for inclusion can be added and included in subsequent versions. See the criteria and data submission sections below for details.
 Data Data access and LiPDverse visualizations are available here.
 Publication A data descriptor for the compilation was published in Earth System Science Data and is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iso2k</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/project/iso2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/project/iso2k/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Iso2k database compiled the stable oxygen (\(\delta^{18}O\)) and hydrogen (\(\delta^{2}H\)) isotopic compositions of environmental waters such as precipitation, seawater, lake water, and soil and groundwater, as recorded in a variety of natural archives, including glaciers, ground ice, cave formations, corals, sclerosponges, mollusk shells, tree wood, lake sediments, and marine sediments. This is a dynamic compilation, meaning that new datasets that meet the criteria for inclusion can be added and included in subsequent versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PalMod</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/project/palmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/project/palmod/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The PalMod data compilation is a multi-parameter marine palaeoclimate data synthesis that contains time series spanning 0 to 130,000 years ago. The compilation includes only time series for which a robust chronology based on benthic foraminifera \(\delta^{18}O\) and radiocarbon dating is available. Version 1.0.0 of the data product contains 896 time series from 143 individual sites, each associated with rich metadata, age–depth model ensembles, and information to refine and update the chronologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature 12k</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/project/temp12k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/project/temp12k/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The Temperature 12k database was compiled to facilitate the study of multidecadal- to millennial-scale changes in climate over the past 12,000 years. This is a dynamic compilation, meaning that new datasets that meet the criteria for inclusion can be added and included in subsequent versions. See the criteria and data submission sections below for details.
 PAGES 2k Data Coverage   Data Data access and LiPDverse visualizations are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAGES 2k Temperature</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/project/pages2k/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/project/pages2k/</guid>
      <description>PAGES 2k Data Coverage   Introduction One of the products of Phase Two of the Pages2k project was this curated data product of temperature reconstructions for the past 2000 years. This is a dynamic compilation, meaning that new datasets that meet the criteria for inclusion can be added and included in subsequent versions. See the criteria and data submission sections below for details.
Data Data access and LiPDverse visualizations are available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Background Since 2010, when we first started discussing how frustrating and redundant it was to organize and format paleoclimate data, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working towards the LiPDverse, and the rest of the &amp;ldquo;LiPD Ecosystem&amp;rdquo; of data, analysis and visualization tools. Early on this was mostly complaining to likeminded colleagues, then we started envisioning what a good solution might look like, then it became a hobby, and starting in 2014 we received our first round of funding from the National Science Foundation to support paleoclimate informatics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://lipdverse.org/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lipdverse.org/faq/</guid>
      <description>1. What is LiPD? 2. Why LiPD? 3. Where can I find LiPD datasets? 4. Is LiPDverse a long-term data repository? 5. How do I do I get my data into LiPD? 6. How do I contribute data to lipdverse and/or into a project? 7. How do I give appropriate credit to the original studies behind these data and project compilations? 8. How do I give credit to LiPDverse?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
